MD.THORAT ISLAM

34/4, Ahammadbug, Bashaboo, Shobujbaug -1214. WebSite: https://zasusoft.com, Basabo TSO, Sabujbagh, Dhaka 1214

01517123534, 01307435890

mdthoratislam1993.oni@gmail.com



Career Objective:

To build a career in Information and Communication technology with the experience that I have gained from my education and professional background willing to take any challenge in the relevant field.

Career Summary:

#Excellent knowledge of developing web applications and websites. # Career oriented, hardworking and ability to handle multiple tasks. # Developing and creating PHP MySQL application as per the specifications. # Quick learner and ability to learn new concept. # Experience on coordinating with team members in database structure # Passionate about giving best design and coding practices

Special Qualification:

Professional Web Application Development (PWAD): Islamic Development Bank-Bangladesh Islamic Solidarity Educational Wakf(IDB-BISEW) IT Scholarship ProjectAuthority: IDB-BISEWDuration: 460 hrsEarned On: June, 2021

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 5 yrs

1. Full stack Developer (0.4 yr)

(11 Nov 2023 - Continuing)

Smart Think

Area of Expertise:

API Development (0.3 yr), Laravel Framework (0.3 yr), Vue JS (0.3 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities:

Programming languages: PHP, JavaScript

Frameworks: Laravel, Vue.js Database management: MySQL

Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs

Version control: Git

Development tools: Composer, npm, VSCode, PhpStorm

Server management: Laragon

Database management tools: MySQL HeidiSQL

Command-line interface: Git Bash

2. Executive (Software Developer) (1.3 yrs)

(25 Aug 2022 - 7 Nov 2023)

Blue Planet Group

Area of Expertise:

Laravel and Vue.js (1.2 yrs), Oracle Database (1.2 yrs), PHP (OOP) (1.2 yrs)

Duties/Responsibilities:

Programming languages: Core Php, JavaScript

Database management:MySql and ORACLE Database 12c Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript,JQuery, Ajax

Version control: Git

Development tools: Composer, npm, VSCode, PhpStorm

Server management: Laragon

Database management tools: MySQL HeidiSQL

Command-line interface: Git Bash

3. Junior Software Engineer (0.7 yr)

(15 Dec 2021 - 31 Jul 2022) **Logic Software Limited**

Area of Expertise:

JavaScript (0.6 yr), Oracle Database (0.6 yr), PHP (OOP) (0.6 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities:

Programming languages: Core Php, JavaScript Database management: ORACLE Database 12c

Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax

Version control: Git

Development tools: VSCode Server management: Laragon

Database management tools: MySQL Command-line interface: Git Bash

4. Executive (2.6 yrs)

(9 Nov 2017 - 31 May 2020)

Unique Eastern Pvt. Ltd. concern of Unique Group

Area of Expertise:

IT (Application) (2.5 yrs)

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pas.Year	Duration	Achievement
Bachelor of Science (BSc)	Computer Science & Information Technology	University of South Asia	CGPA:3.35 out of 4	2021	3	2021
Diploma in Engineering	Telecommunication	F.K. Polytechnic Institute	CGPA:2.4 out of 4	2015	4	2015
SSC	Business Studies	Kamlapur High School	CGPA:3.31 out of 5	2010	-	-

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
Professional Web Application Development	CF, HTML5, CSS3,Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP(OOP)/MySQL, JQuery, WrodPress, Laravel	IDB-bisew	Bangladesh	Sher-e-Bangla Nagar. Dhaka- 1207, Bangladesh	2021	6 Months
Web Development	Word press. HTML.CSS, PHP, MySQL	Institute Of Information Technology (DU)	Bangladesh	University of dhaka	2015	3 Months

bdjobs-amcat Employability Certificates:

Job Role	Test Date
Information Technology (C# Programming, English Comprehension, Logical Ability, Personality, Quantitative Ability)	26 Aug 2020

Professional Qualification:

Certification	Institute	Location	From	То
Professional Web Application Development	IDB-bisew	Sher-e-Bangla Nagar. Dhaka- 1207, Bangladesh	December 9, 2020	May 27, 2021
WordPress	Institute Of Information Technology Under University of Dhaka	University of dhaka	September 1, 2014	November 30, 2014

Career and Application Information:

Looking For : Mid Level Job Available For : Full Time Expected Salary : Tk. 70000

Preferred Job Category : IT/Telecommunication

Preferred District : Chattogram, Dhaka, Gazipur, Narayanganj

Preferred Country : Australia, Canada, Italy, Malaysia

Skill:

Fields of Skill	Description
 PHP (OOP) HTML5 and CSS3 Laravel and Vue.js Bootstrap and other Scripting Languages RESTful API Git Version Control System PHP MySql JS JQuery AJAX Oracle Database 	Professional Web Application Development (PWAD): Islamic Development Bank-Bangladesh Islamic Solidarity Educational Wakf (IDB-BISEW) IT Scholarship Project Authority: IDB- BISEW Duration: 460 hrs Earned On: June, 2021

Extra Curricular Activities:

FSCD Volunteer Training,

Fire Fighting, Earthquake Awareness, First Aid and Emergency Rescue.

Bangladesh Fire Service and civil Defense.

Khilgaon Fire Station, Khilgaon, Dhaka.

2014-48 hours

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Bangle	High	High	High
English	High	High	Medium

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Abu Hossain Mother's Name : Parvin Nahar Date of Birth : 4 May 1995 Gender : Male Height (Meter) : 5.1 Weight (Kg) : 72 Marital Status : Married Nationality : Bangladeshi Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : Dhanua Kamalpur, Basabo TSO, Bakshiganj, Jamalpur 1214

Current Location : Dhaka Blood Group : AB+

Reference (s):

Reference: 01 Reference: 02

Name : Mohammad Towhidul Islam MD. Moshaidul Islam IDB-BISEW IT Scholarship

Organization : Intellect Software Ltd Project

Designation : CEO Project Consultant

Primary Mobile No : 01715785434 01711071219

Primary Email : towhidsir@yahoo.com moshaidul@gmail.com

Relation : Academic Academic